American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe. 1845-1865 APS.Archives.IIe APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, November 18, 1852; 8" x 10"; Patterson, Robert M. (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    Philadelphia 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Wishes to decline again being a candidate for presidency of the A.P.S. Printed in Pro., V, 293.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 20, 1852; 11x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Trendelenberg. 1p.,end.by F.F[isher]. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Amherst College, November 22, 1852; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Boltwood, Lucius M. (Lucius Manlius), 1825-1905
    1 p., address and endorsement. Requests a copy of A.P.S. Proceedings, no. 46, which has not yet been received by Amherst College.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Nov. 30, 1852; 10x8; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Barlow. 3p.,end.by J.F.F.[isher]. Forwards publications and lists the APS publications it has and needs.
  - Letter to Magyar Tudományos Akadémia Konyvtára, Nov., 1852; 9-1/2x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Xerox of printed L.S.: Charles B. Trego. 1p (From original in Magyar Tudományos...; 1968.) Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, December 13, 1852; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Bache, Hartman, 1797-1872
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Offers to send a copy of Magnetic and Meteorological Observations, Girard College, 1840-1845, to the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, December 15, 1852; 8" x 9 15/16"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Secretary of A.P.S., Department of State, Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Returns Dunn's map of the British Empire, 1774, to the A.P.S. See Pro., V, 297.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, December 25, 1852; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Dallas, George Mifflin, 1792-1864
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Sends check for $20, in payment of two years contribution to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, January 2, 1853; 6 13/16" x 8 7/16"; Kennedy, John Pendleton, 1795-1870
    Secretary of A.P.S., Navy Department, Washington, [D. C.], 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns thanks to A.P.S. for resolutions approving use of navy department for "the furtherance of scientific enquiry." Dr. Elisha K. Kane to join arctic expedition. See Pro., V, 299-300, 302.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 4, 1853; 8x5-1/2; École nationale supérieure des mines de Paris
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J. Buchère. 1p.,end. by E.O.K[endall]. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Report of the committee appointed to consider... the laws of the Society, January 7, 1853; 8 1/8" x 12"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: F[rederick] Fraley, J[ohn] K. Kane, Jacob G. Morris.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 8, 1853; 5" x 7 1/2"; Hare, Robert
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 2 pp. A.L.S. Requests that his resignation, "placed in the hands of the committee long since," be accepted.
  - Letter to C. B. Trego, Jan. 11, 1853; 8-1/2x7; Albany Institute
    A.L.S.: J.C.Munsell. 1p.,end.,by E.O. K[endall]. Forwards publications and lists APS publications.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 11, 1853; 5" x 7 11/16"; Bache, Hartman, 1797-1872
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to know of receipt of books from the adjutant general's office.
  - Letter to John F. Frazer, January 12, 1853; 5" x 8"; Lewis, John T.
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. Encloses communication from James S. Olcott on apocalyptic vision, sent to the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts by mistake. John Lindsley, H.R.Phelps, and W[illia]m Tilghman. 4p.,end. 16x9-3/4. (see George Clymer papers.)
  - Letter to L[orin] Blodget, Washington, Jan. 19, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Meriam, Ebenezer, 1794-1864
    Brooklyn Heights; A.L.S. 10p.and end. Meteorological information and earthquakes.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, January 21, 1853; 4 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Parish, George
    Ogdensburgh,N.Y., 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Parish family relinquishes claim to collection of medals deposited with the American Philosophical Society by the late Mr. David Parish. See Pro., V, 310, 313.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, January 22, 1853; 5 3/16" x 7 15/16"; Dillingham, William H., 1791-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Due to need for economy would like to know how " I can be relived from the annual payments" to the A.P.S. except "by tendering my resignation."
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 25, 1853; 5" x 7 11/16"; Bache, Hartman, 1797-1872
    Secretary of A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Election of Major [Alfred] Mordecai to membership in the A.P.S. In re payment of dues.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, January 25, 1853; 7 11/16" x 9 3/4"; Dillingham, William H., 1791-1854
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Concerning his proposed resignation from membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 26, 1853; 5 3/4" x 7 7/16"; Bache, Hartman, 1797-1872
    Washington, 2 pp. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S. library, in the name of H. S. Guyer, a report of a Zoölogical survey of Wisconsin, Iowa, and Minnesota.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 26, 1853; 5 1/8" x 8"; Bache, Hartman, 1797-1872
    Washington, 1 p. Visited commissioner of Indian affairs to get a copy of Schoolcraft's work on Indians for the A.P.S. Found Society already on list.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 28, 1853; 6 3/4" x 8 1/2"; Bache, Hartman, 1797-1872
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Sends a set of a artillery drawings to the A.P.S. library, in the name of Colonel H. K. Craig.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 29, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Bowditch Library
    Boston, A.L.S.: Henry I. Bowditch. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 2, 1853; 9-3/4X7-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John L. LeConte. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Feb. 2, 1853; 10x8; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas.Hosmer. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings. Asks if their publications have been received.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 7, 1853; 10x8
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.H.Smyth. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 8, 1853; 10x8; American Antiquarian Society
    Worcester, A.L.S.: Sam[ue]l F. Haven. 1p.,end.: J. F.F.[isher]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, Feb. 9, 1853; 8-1/2x8; United States. Army
    Washington, L.S.: H.K.Craig. 1p.,end.by J.F.F[isher]. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, Feb. 12, 1853; 5-3/4x7-1/2; New Jersey Historical Society
    Newark, A.L.S.: Samuel H. Congar, 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher]. Thanks for Proceedings
  - Letter to C[harles] B.Trego, Feb. 16, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Townsend Ward. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Charles B.] Trego, Feb. 16, [1853]; 7x4-1/2; Reed, William B. (William Bradford), 1806-1876
    A.L.S. 1p.,end.by J.F.F[isher]. Forwards publication to the APS by Lord Mahon.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 18, 1853; 12x8-1/2; Societas Regia Scientiarum Upsaliensis
    [read] Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E.Jonèv. 2p.,end.by J.F.F[isher]. In French. Forwards publication and thanks for the APS publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 14, 1853; 10x8-1/2; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wiedmann. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall] In German. Forwards publications.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by Dr. [John L.] LeConte, March 19, 1853; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "Classification of the Carabidae of the United States," [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: S[amuel] S. Haldeman, Joseph Leidy, W. S. W. Ruschenberger. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to George M. Justice, March 27, 1853; 6-3/4x4-1/4; Kane, Elisha Kent, 1820-1857
    A.L.S. 3p. Request for aid in raising money for a member of Artic expidition.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, April 6, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Gilliss, J. M. (James Melville), 1811-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.,end.by F.F.[isher] and add. Will forward publications of the university of Chile.
  - Letter to ----, April 8, 1853; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. L. Unsigned. Introducing Professor George B. Wood, deputed to communicate with the scientific and literary institutions and learned men of Europe, enrolled as correspondents of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Dorchester, April 29, 1853; 6x4; Jarvis, Edward, 1803-1884
    A.L.S. 1p.,end.by J.F.F[isher]. Forwards publications.
  - Subscriptions to fund for procuring an Astronomical Observer, April, 1853; American Philosophical Society.
    to accompany Dr. Kane's Expedition to the Artic Region.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, May 21, 1853; Free Public Library (New Bedford, Mass.).
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 23, 1853; 9x6; Königlich Sächsische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig
    Leipzig, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Ernst Heinrich Weber. 1p.,end. by C.B.T[rego]. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Members of the American Philosophical Society living in Paris, May, 1853; 8 1/4" x 9 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Memorandum furnished by Hector Bossange.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], May, 1853; 10-1/2x8-1/2; St. Petersburg. Corp des ingénieurs des mines - État-major du
    St.Petersburg, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], June 4, 1853; 10x8-1/2; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wiedmann. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 9, 1853; 8x5-1/2; École nationale supérieure des mines de Paris
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Buchère. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 11, 1853; 11-1/2x9; Kaiserlich-Königliche Geographische Gesellschaft (Austria)
    Vienna, A.L.S. W.Haidinger. 1p.,end.by C.B T[rego]. Desires to exchange publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 7, 1853; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhaven, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: G. Forchhammer. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] In Danish. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 7, 1853; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Göttingen, A.L.S.: Hausmann. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 13, 1853; 8x5-1/2; École nationale supérieure des mines de Paris
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Buchère. 1p. end. by E.O.K[endall]. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, Secretary of A.P.S., July 17, 1853; 4" x 6 1/4"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Declines to prepare on obituary notice of Dr. Charles Caldwell. See Pro., V, 338.
  - Members of the Amer[ican] Phil[osophica]l society, July 18, 1853; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    supposed to be living in Sweden, Stockholm, 1 p. and endorsement. Memorandum of Mr. Charles D. Arfwedson.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Secretary of A.P.S., July 25, 1853; 4" x 6 1/4"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Declines to prepare an obituary notice of Dr. Philip Tidyman. See Pro., V, 338.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, July 25, 1853; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Y.Akerman. 2p.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John F. Crampton, July 26, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Great Britain. Foreign Office
    Printed L.S.: H.Ch.Addington. 2p.,end.by F.F[isher]. Forwards publications on linguistics.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 29, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L.S.: A. Dudley Mann. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. Forwards publications.
  - Members of the Amer[ican] Phil[osophical] Society... elected as residing in St. Petersburg, July, 1853; 8" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Memorandum of Dr. Alexander Brown.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, August 4, 1853; 7 13/16" X 9 11/16"; Lenthall, John, 1807-1882
    Secretary of A.P.S., Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning the preparation of an obituary notice for the late Samuel Humphreys. See Pro., V, 338.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, August 5, 1853; 8 3/16" x 10 5/8"; Bache, Franklin, 1792-1864
    St. Petersburg, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. News of Russian members of the A.P.S. See Pro., V, 340.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 15, 1853; 11x8-3/4; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Bockh. 1p., end.: C.B.T[rego]. In German. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, August 20, 1853; 4 7/16" x 7 1/8"; Davis, Joseph Barnard, 1801-1881
    Librarian of A.P.S., Shelton, Staffordshire, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Trego, as librarian of the A.P.S., to recommend his work, Crania Britannica. See Pro., V, 342.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 21, 1853; 11-1/2x9; Kaiserlich-Königliche Geographische Gesellschaft (Austria)
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: W.Haidinger. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Aug. 24, 1853; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumüller. 1p. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 25, 1853; 9-3/4x8; Natural History Society of Northumberland, Durham, & Newcastle-upon-Tyne
    Newcastle, L.S.: Edward Charlton and Joseph Blacklock. 1p.,end.: J.F.F.[razer] and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 29, 1853; 10x8; Leeds Philosophical & Literary Society
    Leeds, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: George Shaw 1p.,end,: J.F.F[razer] and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug., 1853; 10-1/4x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: D.W.Mitchell. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher]. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 1, 1853; 9x7-1/2; Royal Institution of Great Britain
  - Letter to [Franklin] Bache, Sept. 1/13, 1853; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Renard. 1p.,end.by F.F[isher]. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Sept. 5, 1853; 10x8; Genoa. Accademia medico-chirurgiga e di scienze naturali
    Genoa, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: G.B.Massone. 1p.,end. by J.F.F[isher], and add. In Italian. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 15, 1853; 11x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Boeckh. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Sept. 15, 1853; 11x8-1/2; Flügel, J. G. (Johann Gottfried), 1788-1855
    Leipzig, L.S. 2p. Lists books forwarded to various institutions in the U.S. Asks how he is to be refunded for postage.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 22, 1853; 10-1/2x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Flourens. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 12, 1853; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Quetelet. 1p. ,end.: C.B.T[rego]. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 18, 1853; 9x7-1/4; Horticultural Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Lindley. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley];and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 28, 1853; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: A. Schrätter 1p.,end.: F[raley]. In German. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Oct. 29, 1853; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumüller. 1p.,end.by C.B.T[rego]. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Nov. 1, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Connecticut Historical Society
  - Letter to the American philosophical society [C. B. Trego] Philadelphia, Nov. 1, 1853; 7-1/2x3-3/4; New Jersey Historical Society
    A.L.S.: Samuel H. Congar. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 1, 1853; 10x8; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: P.F.Wahlberg. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] In French. Thanks for Transactions and lists those missing from its collection.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, Philadelphia, Nov. 2, 1853; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Vrolik. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher]. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to John F.Frazer, Philadelphia, Nov. 2, 1853; 9-3/4x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: James Walker, Pres. and Thaddeus William Harris, Libn. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 3, 1853; 14x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm. J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley],and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by Dr. [John L.] LeConte, November 4, 1853; 6 1/2" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    entitled "Revision of the Elateridae of the United States," [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: S[amuel] S. Haldeman, Cha[rle]s B. Trego, Robert Bridges. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to John F. Fraser [sic], Nov. 4, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; New York State Library
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 8, 1853; 10x8-1/4; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John J. Bennett. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov.10, 1853; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumüller. 1p.,end.by F.F[isher]. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 15, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, November 18, 1853; 8" x 10"; Bache, Franklin, 1792-1864
    Treasurer of A.P.S., ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Contributes $500 to A.P.S. "towards the expense of preparing & printing a correct catalogue of the library... " Printed in Pro., V, 355.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 18, 1853; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Y.Akerman. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley]. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 19, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S: R.Clarke. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley]. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1853; 11-1/2x9-1/2; Kaiserlich-Königliche Geographische Gesellschaft (Austria)
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Haidinger. 1p.,end. by F.F[isher]. In German. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 23, 1853; 10x8; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, Printed L.filled in in ms. S.: P.F.Wahlberg. 1p.,end.by F.F[isher]. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 24, 1853; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Schrätter. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, November 27, 1853; 4 15/16" x 7 13/16"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to have titles of papers read before the A.P.S. or published in the Proceedings by S[ears] C. Walker.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 30, 1853; 8-1/2x5; École nationale supérieure des mines de Paris
    Paris, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J. Buchère. 1p.,end. by F.F[isher]. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 1/13, 1853; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Russia. Observatoire physique central
    St. Petersburg, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: A.Kupffer. 1p.,end.: F.F[raley] and end. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, December 7, 1853; 4 15/16" x 7 13/16"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Wishes to have titles of papers by [Sears C. ] Walker in A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Dec. 12, 1853; 10x8; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Barlow. 2p.,end. by F.F[isher]. 2p.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Philadelphia, Dec. 14, 1853; 13x8; Crampton, John Fiennes Twisleton, Sir, 1805-1886
    Washington, L.S. 2p.,end.by F.F[isher]. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, Dec. 15, 1853; 8x6-1/2; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
    A.L.S. 1p.,end.by F.F[isher]. Deposits publication.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Dec. 16, 1853; 7x4; Dillingham, William H., 1791-1854
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Sends coins for A.P.S. collection, with letter of explanation from J.D. Elliot. For enclosure, see J.D. Elliot to Dillingham, Nov. 4, 1842.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, Dec. 17, 1853; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Sending coins for A.P.S. collection. Refers to W.H. Dillingham.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 17, 1853; 10x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Norton Shaw. 2p.,end.: F.F[raley]. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings